<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>DevX Tools &amp; Modules – meta</title><link>https://puppetlabs.github.io/devx/tags/meta/</link><description>Recent content in meta on DevX Tools &amp; Modules</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://puppetlabs.github.io/devx/tags/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Prm: Telemetry</title><link>https://puppetlabs.github.io/devx/prm/concepts/telemetry/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://puppetlabs.github.io/devx/prm/concepts/telemetry/</guid><description>
&lt;p>By default, PRM collects some telemetry during each run.
This information is non-identifying and does not include any personal or organizational details.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We use it to see how PRM is being used so we can better understand issues, features, and what to prioritize as we move forward.
We emit this telemetry information to &lt;a href="https://honeycomb.io">Honeycomb&lt;/a> for introspection.
We keep the telemetry for 60 days, after which it ages out.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-we-gather">What We Gather&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Each PRM run reports the following data:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The UTC timestamp for when the run started&lt;/li>
&lt;li>How long the command took to run&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The operating system architecture (x64, ARM, etc)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The operating system type (darwin, linux, windows)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A uniquely generated internal identifier for the machine running the command&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Whether or not the command ran in a CI environment&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The arguments passed to PRM in this run&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>This data allows us to see broadly how many machines the program is running on, what the breakdown of operating system/system architecture is, how performant the program is, and which commands are most used.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When there is an error, PRM reports the error information as well - the stack trace information and the error message displayed to a user.
This lets us investigate issues to see how common they are and improve our testing and error handling.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="running-prm-without-telemetry">Running PRM Without Telemetry&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We know that some users do not want to report telemetry;
for those users, it is possible to install a &amp;ldquo;notel&amp;rdquo; version of the binary which does not include the telemetry bits at all.
This binary is identical to the standard binary save that it does not have any mechanisms for recording or sending telemetry data.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For those users, an alternate install is available.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To install:&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="bash">Bash&lt;/h3>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#282a36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">curl -L https://pup.pt/pdkgo/install.sh | sh -s -- --no-telemetry
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;h3 id="powershell">PowerShell&lt;/h3>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#282a36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-powershell" data-lang="powershell">&lt;span style="color:#8be9fd;font-style:italic">iex &lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#f1fa8c">&amp;#34;&amp;amp;{ &lt;/span>$(&lt;span style="color:#8be9fd;font-style:italic">irm &lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#f1fa8c">&amp;#39;https://pup.pt/pdkgo/install.ps1&amp;#39;&lt;/span>)&lt;span style="color:#f1fa8c">; Install-Pct -NoTelemetry }&amp;#34;&lt;/span>
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Pct: About PCT</title><link>https://puppetlabs.github.io/devx/pct/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://puppetlabs.github.io/devx/pct/about/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="overview">Overview&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Puppet Content Templates (PCT) codify a structure to produce content for any Puppet Product that can be authored by Puppet Product Teams or external users without direct help of the PDK team.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>PCT can create any type of a Puppet Product project: Puppet control repo, Puppet Module, Bolt project, etc. It can create one or more independent files, such as CI files or gitignores. This can be as simple as a name for a Puppet Class, a set of CI files to add to a Puppet Module, or as complex as a complete Puppet Control repo with roles and profiles.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>These are meant to be ready-to-run, which means they put everything needed for a user to run the project from the moment after creation. This solves the &amp;lsquo;blank page&amp;rsquo; problem, where a few files are in place but the user does not know what the next steps are.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Note:&lt;/strong>
PCT is currently in an EXPERIMENTAL phase and feedback is encouraged via &lt;a href="https://github.com/puppetlabs/pdkgo/discussions">pdkgo/discussions&lt;/a> and starting a &lt;code>feedback&lt;/code> post.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Pct: Contact DevX about PCT</title><link>https://puppetlabs.github.io/devx/pct/contact/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://puppetlabs.github.io/devx/pct/contact/contact/</guid><description>
&lt;h2 id="requesting-a-feature">Requesting a feature&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Open a new feature request in our &lt;a href="https://github.com/puppetlabs/pdkgo/issues/new">Github discussion&lt;/a> page.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="reporting-problems">Reporting Problems&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>If you&amp;rsquo;re having trouble with the experimental PCT tool, please follow these instructions
to file an issue on our GitHub repository: &lt;a href="https://github.com/puppetlabs/pdkgo/issues/new">https://github.com/puppetlabs/pdkgo/issues/new&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Make sure to fill in the information that is requested in the issue template as it
will help us investigate the problem more quickly.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>